Caesar Solano Lagunas | Full Stack Software Engineer

San Diego, CA | (619) 245-3906 | caesars|1904@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Github | Portfolio

Professional Summary

Passionate Software Engineer with a broad set of technical and intrapersonal skills that is ready to develop innovative solutions. Self-started business owner that has been faced with real-world problems which allowed to take initiative in solving various problems. Customer success oriented, communicating with guests to leave them with a remarkable experience. Recent General Assembly Software Engineer Immersive graduate that prepared myself to write clean and effective code to create responsive user interfaces.

Skills

Languages - Python, JavaScript (ES6), HTML5, CSS

Libraries & Frameworks - React, Axios, Node.js, Express, EJS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Handlebars, Jest

Spoken Languages - Spanish(Fluent), English(Fluent)

Database - PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, DjangoDB | Other - RESTful Routing, API's, Auth0 2.0

Tools/Platforms - Github, Git, Photoshop, Illustrator, Postman, Herouku,, Netlify, CLI, Netlify, Slack, Zoom, Microsoft 365, Google Search, Agile workflow, Trello, SDLC

Certifications - Comptia A+ certification

Software Engineering Projects

Health Hero (MERN Stack) | ReactJS, Express, MongoDB, Node.js

July 2022 - July 2022

- Lead team as project manager, performed daily stand ups and meetings to ensure a clear goal.
- Implemented API with ability to search the number of calories for any food item.
- Reached extended goals within 1 week of deadline by creating collaborative environments such as peer coding.

Simpsons Catalog (CRUD app) | HTML, CSS, Vanilla Javascript

March 2022 - March 2022

- Catalog application allows users to keep a collection of characters, users are allowed to favorite certain characters.
- Incorporated RestfulAPI's into the web application along with MongoDB in order to interact with the database.
- Responsibilities include designing, developing, testing, debugging, and deploying features.

Tower of Hanoi (Game) | HTML, CSS, Vanilla Javascript

April 2022 - April 2022

- Recursion game where users can play with anti-cheating mechanisms.
- Performed daily stand-ups in order to understand the insights of coding practices.
- Wireframing along with effective communication to ensure the goal was clean and direct.

Professional Experience

Owner | El Chavo, Ice Cream Truck | San Diego, CA

July 2012 - PRESENT

- Established fully self-sufficient business within 1 month time by creating daily timed routes.
- Implemented daily profitable purchases based on daily sales and most sold items.
- Deployed functionality for mobile payment via technologies including Square, Venmo, and nfc payment.

Warehouse Associate | Specialty Produce | San Diego, CA

October 2020 - July 2022

- Verified ~115 products daily, checked quality of products by examining and making sure it is restaurant quality.
- Operated heavy machinery, moved over 10,000 lbs daily in fast-paced environment
- Processed over 200 shipping and receiving orders daily and delivered products within a 3 hour timed route.

FOH Management | Chick-fil-A | San Diego, CA

June 2016 - October 2020

- Supervised twenty person team through shift and incorporated new employees into the team.
- Increased the drive-thru sales intake by over 200% by simplifying the process to be more efficient.
- Communicated all repair and maintenance needs with the appropriate third parties.

Education

General Assembly January 2022 - July 2022

Software Engineering Immersive (remote)

Full-stack software engineering immersive fellow in an intensive, 24-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

San Diego Mesa Community College Associates Degree in Nursing

July 2016 - August 2020